Today's the day I'll finally ask
Kamegawa out for drinks.
"As..."
"As a thank-you for lending me your
umbrella, want to go out for drinks?"
"As a thank-you for
lending me your umbrella..."
Would it be better if I said it's my treat?
Hmm...
So then I entered the raffle, and I won!
Wow! That's amazing!
Kamegawa and... Who is that?
Maybe a new hire like him?
I bet it's easier to get along with
people in the same age group.
Huh?!
Wait, why am I feeling down about this?
As a mature adult, I should be happy
to see coworkers getting along smoothly.
You got this, Kamegawa!
A fireworks festival, huh? I'm excited!
You should be thankful
for my insanely good luck!
Thank you, O great Hotta-sama!
It's been a while since
I went to see fireworks.
Guess I'll invite him out
for drinks some other time.
What's this? Are you guys going
to the fireworks festival, too?
Wha—
Can we go with you?
What?!
MY AWKWARD SENPAI
EPISODE 6:
A YUKATA IS THE NORM FOR FIREWORKS FESTIVALS
"A Yukata Is the Norm For Fireworks Festivals."
Who butts into the conversation
of a couple of coworkers
hyped up about goin' to see the fireworks?!
Are they insane?!
Don't get in their way!
Oh, yes. If you two don't mind.
We may be in different departments,
but this would be a nice opportunity
to get to know each other.
Whaddya mean, "get to know each other"?!
Read the room! Idiot!
Thank you. I feel the same.
Where should we meet up?
Can we pick the spot?
Um...
I'll leave that to you, then.
Oh, no!
They're going deeper into the plan!
Give me your contact info, then.
Hey.
This fireworks festival...
Mind if I join you?
Oh, um... Not at all...
Oh! But it'll be harder to
get around in a larger group!
Y-You're right!
We'll have to skip it this time.
Maybe next time!
Later.
What? Um, okay...
HEH, HEH, HEH
Behold.
A skill that's only achievable
for people who are outcasts...
SOBS
Um, Senpai...
I was lying about wanting to go.
Don't worry about it.
Huh?
It's your long-awaited fireworks festival.
You two should enjoy it together.
Could it be that...
they actually wanted to go with those two?!
If this turns out to be a
huge misunderstanding, I...
Oh, no... I should have
minded my own business.
Um, Senpai!
Wh-What is it?
Would you like to join us, Senpai?
At the fireworks festival!
Nice to meet you. I'm Mio Hotta.
I'm in the Public Relations Department
and started at the same time as Kamegawa.
It's a pleasure to make your acquaintance!
I'm Azusa Kannawa.
It feels as if it's not our first time meeting.
PUBLIC RELATIONS DEPARTMENT - MIO HOTTA
I've heard so much about you from Kamegawa.
Hey!
Senpai's busy, so let's
move on to the festival...
I was able to win the seated spots
for this fireworks festival!
FIREWORKS FESTIVAL - ENTRY RESULTS
ENTRY RESULTS
WINNER - CONGRATULATIONS
Wow.
I didn't know fireworks festivals these
days needed reservations in advance.
Well, not like I've been to
one since I was a li'l kid.
Hotta suggested that we new
hires should all go together.
Huh? All the new hires?
Yes, ma'am!
All six of us, including Kamegawa and me.
So it wasn't gonna be just the two of 'em...
No, wait.
It's gonna awkward insertin'
myself in a group of six juniors.
Wouldn't it be better for the newbies
to have fun with each other
without an outsider like me?
Please don't worry about it!
I've been wanting to talk with you
for a while now, Kannawa-senpai!
Wh-Why?
Aren't we talking right now?
Oh, I'm sure Senpai must be
tired and all, so... Right?
I'm looking forward to it, Kannawa-senpai!
Y-Yeah. Me, too.
It's a festival, so...
Of course people would wear yukata.
I've no idea what would be good.
Come to think of it, I do have that one
Mom bought me ages ago that I never wore.
MOM - CALLING
Hello!
Hi, Mom—
Getting a call from you is so rare, Azusa-chan!
UGH...
Are you doin' good?
Are ya off work for the day?
What's the matter?
Oh, yeah, um... Hey, Mom?
That yukata you got me a while back—
Yukata!
That yukata, yeah!
It was love at first sight, so I bought it.
But you ended up movin' to Tokyo
without even wearin' it once.
Wait! Do you need it?
Yeah. So could ya send me
a photo of the yukata?
Could it be a date?!
No!
I-I'm just going to a fireworks festival
with some people from work!
Really?
I guess some work places do that.
Oh, I just sent ya the photo!
Never mind. Sorry.
It's a li'l too cutesy for me.
Really?
I even have the hair piece, bag,
and geta that go with it!
Oh. Then can you send me those?
Okay!
I'll send ya some cash,
so go buy yourself a new yukata!
I'm a working adult.
It's okay. I can buy it with my own money.
Yer right!
Since all you do is play games and never leave
the house, you've got the money to spend!
Wh-Whoa...
I dunno what to pick, or how...
I don't even know what I'm doing
when I need to buy normal clothes.
Are you shopping for a yukata today?
This area is our new release section.
What kind of style are you looking for?
I'm all right.
Please feel free to let me
know if you need any help.
Sure.
I'm so sorry, Ms. Employee Person...
She's just doin' her job...
Kame (turtle)...
I wonder what Kamegawa will...
Wait! Why was I reminded of Kamegawa?!
It's okay!
I may not know what to wear,
but I need something!
In situations like this...
Excuse me! I'll take this one!
EVEN BEGINNERS CAN DO IT!!
HOW TO PUT ON A YUKATA
Hm?
The right side goes over the
top and... the left is under?
Wait, which is which for me right now?
H-Here? Hm? Huh?
I thought I could do this by myself,
but I could use two more hands!
AN HOUR LATER
I can't do this...
Skitter, skitter...
Oh? Good morning, Kannawa-senpai!
M-May I speak with you for a bit?
Of course!
You see... About the fireworks festival...
Huh?!
Could it be that you have other plans?
No, I don't!
I bought a yukata, and...
What? Are you going to wear a yukata, Senpai?
Aren't you?
I was thinking of just
going in my regular clothes.
I-I could have just chosen to
wear my normal clothes?
AAAAAAAHHH
Since I went out to get a yukata,
now I look like someone
who's super excited to go!
If you're going to wear a yukata,
I'll wear mine, too!
Huh?
Well, I was also thinking of wearing
one since it's a good opportunity,
but I figured everyone else would
be wearing regular clothes,
so I thought if I was the only
one wearing a yukata...
Which is why I'm so happy to hear
that you're going to wear yours!
R-Really?
Oh, sorry.
You were saying... about buying a yukata?
Oh, um... How are you going to put it on?
Hmm...
Some salons can get you ready along
with your yukata if you bring it, I think?
But nowadays, there are tutorial videos online.
Just watch those and you'll be set!
Yeah, I suppose.
All right. Time to make a salon reservation.
Hey!
I was just chatting with Kannawa-senpai.
With Senpai?
What?
Look forward to Kannawa-senpai in a yukata!
Huh?
Senpai in a yukata! Senpai in a yukata!
H-Hey!
A yukata...
TODA-KOEN STATION
You guys arrived early today!
Of course we did!
The notorious Kannawa-senpai
is coming, right?
There's no way we can be late if she'll be here.
Yeah!
So, how is she?
What do you mean?
People say she's good at her job,
but she's also really scary.
Well, it's true that she takes her job
seriously and can be strict...
It's amazing that you can
be friendly and hang out
with someone like that privately.
Kamegawa-kun is friendly and kind, after all.
It's not because I'm kind,
but because Senpai's—
Oh! Kannawa-senpai!
Hey! Kannawa-senpai!
Sorry to keep you all waiting.
Senpai! That yukata is super cute!
Yours, too.
Did you dress yourself?
Yes! I did my best by following a tutorial!
I'm Kannawa, Kamegawa's mentor.
I'm joining you all today
thanks to Hotta's kind invitation.
But please don't mind me.
Just enjoy yourselves.
Good! I was able to say it
just like I practiced!
It's nice to meet you!
Then... let me introduce
you to my colleagues.
I'm Takeda.
I'm Tsukano.
I'm Takigami.
I'm Otake.
There you have it.
Hey, now.
Come on!
You can do better, Kamegawa.
Get it together!
It's nice to meet you all!
There's still time before the fireworks.
We should get something to snack on!
Agreed.
We can get something
at the food stalls up ahead.
YAKISOBA - CHICKEN GYOZA
CHEWY MEAT SKEWER STICKS
TAKOYAKI - YAKISOBA
YAKISOBA
Since we have so many people,
let's split into two groups and shop around.
Got it.
Kamegawa-kun, Hotta-san,
and Kannawa-san can be a group.
Okay!
I told 'em not to worry about me,
but I guess they can't avoid it.
I feel bad.
NORMAL - ONION - MAYO - CHEESE - EGG
Is there anything you want to eat, Senpai?
Cold noodles.
Cold noodles?!
TAKOYAKI - YAKISOBA MADE FOR KINGS
What about takoyaki, Senpai?
If we're eating festival foods,
doughy stuff is the best!
No objections!
Oh, but I want to try a bunch of stuff,
so is it okay if we buy one
of each thing and share?
If Senpai is okay with that.
Go buy some with this.
What?
No, we couldn't!
Yeah!
You guys invited me to your hangout.
This is the least I can do.
But this is outside of work...
Stall food isn't cheap!
FLASH
If you get too caught up in buying stuff,
you'll be broke before you know it!
Thank you so much!
We get the whole wallet! She's so cool!
Let's eat while they're still hot, Senpai!
Yeah.
Let's eat!
A-Aren't they hot?
They are, but...
If you eat them and
simultaneously inhale air...
S-Senpai! Are you okay?!
Water! Something to drink!
Oh, no! I don't have any!
I'll go buy something!
Much better...
S-Sorry to make you worry.
I'm sorry I said they were okay.
What a relief.
I wonder why stall foods are so tasty.
It's gotta be the vibes.
They also have foods that
you wouldn't normally eat.
But even so, I feel like
I eat yakisoba regularly.
I bet it's just instant yakisoba!
Especially since you had
to budget your food
during training because
you bought some toys.
Did you know that, Kannawa-senpai?
That Kamegawa likes plastic model kits.
Oh, I knew that.
She knows!
Senpai knows!
Besides, I'm cooking my own
meals as much as I can now.
Really?
Yes, really!
Huh... So Kamegawa can talk like this...
Well, sure. We can leave it at that.
What do you mean we "can"?
I guess anyone would pretend
they're doing better.
Oh! Shooting!
What do you say, Senpai?
A match between the three of us!
You two go ahead. I'll watch.
Really?
Is there anything you want, then, Senpai?
Huh?
Um...
I'm not going to hold back!
That's my line.
What'll it be, Kannawa-senpai?
Th-Then...
One of the plushies...
Got it!
Huh? I can't hit it...
Just a little more...
Hey! That's the one I'm after!
They're both good juniors... And so kind.
I know that I'm in the wrong
for having these thoughts... but...
I can't bring myself to
be a part of their world.
What am I doin'?
What am I thinkin'?
And what am I feelin'?
I'll just wander around on my own.
And later, when we regroup,
I can say I got lost or something...
Now I've done it.
And now I'm really lost.
If I can just make it to the
fireworks festival grounds...
Huh?
Oh, no! I forgot to charge my phone!
I should've bought new geta instead.
I'm used to being alone, but...
Even on field trips,
I always ate my meals alone.
And on school trips, I'd stray from
my group to spend time by myself.
So then...
Why do I feel so down?
Kamegawa's just my junior.
There's no reason for me to get along
with him more than I need to.
So why?
Oh! There she is!
I looked all over for you, Kannawa-senpai!
Hotta...
You had me worried,
disappearing all of a sudden.
Whoa!
Your strap's broken!
Sorry.
I got distracted by this and then
realized I was separated from you two.
No, no! I'm sorry I didn't notice!
No, I'm really sorry.
Your phone's dead, right, Kannawa-senpai?
I'll let Kamegawa know.
O-Okay.
Oh, I found her. Under the Toda Bridge.
Yeah. Call me again if you can't find it.
Kamegawa was super worried.
He's been looking all over for you.
What?
I'm sorry.
I intruded on your get-together
only for this to happen...
It's really okay!
In fact, I'm honored to
be able to talk with you!
You were saying that before, too.
But there's nothing to gain
from talking with me.
That's not true!
Kamegawa says so all the time!
Whenever he opens his mouth,
he says stuff like, "Senpai is nice,"
or "Senpai taught me this in detail."
He always follows up
with "thanks to Senpai."
He really respects you, Kannawa-senpai.
But you know... since I'm in a
different department from you two...
To be honest, I often heard the
opposite about you from the rumors.
Like how you were scary and strict.
But he's not the kind of guy
to tell lies, so I believed him.
And then I wanted to try
talking to you, as well.
That's enough.
You can stop with the flattery.
So Kamegawa was right all along, huh?
Wh-What gave you that impression?
Kannawa-senpai!
Kamegawa.
I was so worried.
Extremely worried!
Oh, um...
No need to go into the details!
She's found. That's what matters.
Besides, the fireworks are starting soon!
We need to hurry.
Oh, sorry, but could you two go on ahead?
My geta strap broke.
What?!
I forgot!
Let me look something up.
Let's see. You can use a handkerchief and...
a five-yen coin...
I'm going to borrow your wallet again, Senpai.
What? Now?
Can I ask for a five-yen coin?
I think we can do a temporary fix,
so I'm going to try it.
Okay.
Twist up a handkerchief
until it's like a rope...
5 YEN
Put it through a five-yen coin,
then slip it from the bottom of the shoe...
Flip it over and tie them up, and then...
It's done!
It should be fine now.
This will work!
I'm so glad. Shall we get going, then?
Yeah.
Yup!
We can still catch the first shot!
Hold on, Hotta!
If you pull her around like that,
the strap could...
But you fixed it up, right?
It's only a temporary fix!
It could come undone!
Don't get separated.
Yes, ma'am.
EAST A SEATING AREA - EAST B SEATING AREA
Do you see Otake over there? That's our spot.
Yeah. Gotcha.
I'm going to go buy some drinks.
Please go on ahead.
S-Sorry!
No worries.
Um, I'm sorry about earlier.
What?
I spoke so harshly to you when I didn't
even realize your strap was broken.
It's so impressive from up close.
Yeah.
Would I have been able to tell him
if I was his colleague and not his senpai?